<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?> 
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../../../stylesheets/xml2html.xsl"?>
<DOC>
<rdf:RDF xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#">
  <rdf:Description xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
                   xmlns:dcq="http://purl.org/dc/qualifiers/1.0/"
		   about="feasibility.xml">
    <dc:description about="feasibility.html">
      A Feasibility Report of PDF Versions of US Code Project 
      reporting on software, design, and cost/benefit analysis.
    </dc:description>
    <dc:title>Feasibility Study</dc:title>
    <dc:date>
      <rdf:Description 
	dcq:dateType="created" 
	dcq:dateScheme="W3C-DTF"
	rdf:value="2003-10-15"/>
      </dc:date>
      <dc:date>
	<rdf:Description
	  dcq:dateType="modified" 
	  dcq:dateScheme="W3C-DTF"
	  rdf:value="2003-10-15"/>
      </dc:date>
      <dc:creator rdf:about="kalreichi@hotmail.com">
	justin tung
      </dc:creator>
  </rdf:Description>
</rdf:RDF>
<HTMLPAGE>

  <BODY>
  
    <CONTENT>

      <h1>CS 501 - Software Engineering
	<br/>
	Feasibility Report
      </h1>
      
      <h2>Project for the Cornell Legal Information Institute
	<br/>
	PDF versions of the United States Code 
      </h2>

      <p>
	Version 1.1 (revised)<br/>
	November 3 2003<br/>
	Project <a href="cs501.html">Homesite</a>
      </p>
      
      <p class="resume">
      <b>Key stakeholders/organizations :</b><br/>
	<b>Developer Team: </b>
	Tsung-Yueh Chiou, Tsee Yuan Lee, Kohsuke Kawaguchi, Soyeon Kim, Justin Tung
	<br/>
	<b>Project sponsors: </b>Thomas Bruce, Professor William Arms
      </p>

      <hr/>
      
      <p>
	<b>Table Contents</b>
	<br/>
	I. Introduction
	<ol>
	  <li><a href="#po">Project Outline</a></li>
	  <li><a href="#scope">Scope</a></li>
	  <li><a href="#pr">Project Relations</a></li>
	  <li><a href="#bene">Benefits</a></li>
	</ol>
      </p>
      <p>
	II. Software Development Plan
	<ol>
	  <li><a href="#con">Constraints</a></li>
	  <li><a href="#oandr">Obstacles and Risk</a></li>
	  <li><a href="#deliv">Deliverables</a></li>
	  <li><a href="#ppro">Project Process</a></li>
	  <li><a href="#res">Resources</a></li>
	</ol>
      </p>
      
      <hr/>

      <h3>I. Introduction</h3>
      
      <a name="po"/><h4>1. Project Outline</h4>
      
      <p>
	The United States Code is released to the general public by the US House of
	Representatives on its Web site at <a href="http://uscode.house.gov/download.htm">
	  http://uscode.house.gov/download.htm</a>. 
	This code is a plain-vanilla ASCII version to which the Legal Information 
	Institute (http://lii.law.cornell.edu/) adds value. This website is at: <br/>
	
	<a href="http://www4.law.cornell.edu/uscode/">http://www4.law.cornell.edu/uscode/.</a>
      </p>
	
      <p>
	An earlier CS 501 team (Legal Data Markup Software Project) and a later
	student project developed programs for the Legal Information Institute (LII) 
	that convert the raw ASCII output of the House of Representatives to XML, for
	subsequent reuse in various settings. This XML is then converted to HTML
	producing the current website. This conversion was facilitated by XSLT scripts.
	The existing web user interface supports a search engine, HTML legal code,
	cross-referencing, and notes on each section of the code. The US Code currently 
	gets about half a million hits daily. 
      </p>
      
      <p>
	The new project, overseen by Thomas Bruce, Co-Director of the Legal Information 
	Institute, is to create PDF versions of code from the existing XML. In the
	current website, users navigate through HTML links to see the leaves of the 
	legal code tree, which are called 'sections'. Our goal is to implement a 
	system where user can pick sections and more larger divisions (called as 
	'chapter' or 'part') via a shopping cart system. The new PDF format adds 
	printability and portability to the legal code, which was hard to achieve with
	the HTML version. The cart functionality will be integrated into the existing 
	website and will be present in each HTML page of legal code. The idea is then to 
	possibly charge the user for the service followed by on-the-fly XML to PDF
	conversion using XSL. Then the generated PDF documents containing the sections 
	of code requested by the user along with additional information (e.g. table of
	contents, notes, cross-referencing) will be delivered to the user.
      </p>
      
      <a name="scope"/><h4>2. Scope</h4>
      
      <p>
	Required
	<ul>
	  <li>Pre-generate PDFs for bottom elements of legal code tree</li>
	  <li>Pre-generate PDFs for larger divisions</li>
	  <li>Modify existing XSLT script to incorporate PDF functionality in 
	    existing website</li>
	</ul>
      </p>
      <p>
	Desired<br/>
	PDF generation of US legal code for either:
	
	<ul>
	  <li>on-the-fly PDF generation</li>
	  <li>an extensible caching-queuing framework</li>
	  <li>Shopping cart payment system and charging scheme for PDFs</li>
	</ul>
      </p>
      <p>
	Optional
	<ul>
	  <li>Database to support queuing and to track user statistics</li>
        </ul>
      </p>

      <a name="pr"/><h4>3. Project Relations</h4>
      
      <p>
	Another team is working at LII on improving XML format of US code
	but does not directly affect our project.
      </p>
      
      <a name="bene"/><h4>4. Benefits</h4>

      <p>
	<ul>
	  <li>Convenience of legal code in a PDF format available to public as supposed
	    to website format</li>
	  <li>Ability to provide an organized format for legal code in PDF for 
	    printing purposes</li>	  
	  <li>Shopping cart payment system for LII</li>
        </ul>
      </p>
      <hr/>
      
      <h3>II. Software Development Plan</h3>

 
      <a name="con"/><h4>1. Constraints</h4>

      <p>
	The project is funded by Red Hat, therefore the client expressed a preference 
	to rely solely on open-source software. Given the number of visitors to the 
	website (approx. 9 million per week), the system must be able to handle the
	large volume. Experience-wise, the project team must learn new programming 
	languages and environments.
      </p>
      
      <a name="oandr"/><h4>2. Obstacles and Risk</h4>
      
      <p>
	<b>i.</b> Scalability
	<br/>
	At this moment we are not sure whether the currently deployed shopping cart
	system can handle a large number of code sections which we will need to handle. 
	Also, it is not clear how many users will use this PDF service. Given the number
	of visitors to the website, the load of the system can be huge.
      </p>
      <p>
	<b>ii.</b> Lack of Experience
	<br/>
	The developers' need to learn several systems and technologies is apparent in 
	several areas. The production system is running on Linux, but none of the team
	members has good Linux background. The project needs to use various XML-related 
	technologies and CVS fairly extensively, but most of the team members need to
	learn those technologies and CVS. In addition, none of the team members has
	experience working with the shopping cart system and the payment system currently
	deployed. Regarding legacy systems, the existing system that produces HTML from
	US code has to be changed, therefore the team must spend some resources to become
	knowledgeable about it.
      </p>
      <p>
	<b>iii.</b> Integration with existing systems
	<br/>
	The new system might need to coordinate with the currently deployed shopping 
	cart system. However, at this moment we are not sure if this system provides
	such a coordination mechanism.
      </p>
      <p>
	<b>iv.</b> US Legal Code Complexities
	<br/>
	The code contains many irregularities in structure and data organization.
	Also, the DTD does not capture the precise semantics of the code.
      </p>

      <a name="deliv"/><h4>3. Deliverables</h4>
      <p>
	<ul>
	  <li>Feasibility Report</li>
	  <li>Requirements Analysis</li>
	  <li>Prototype</li>
	  <li>System and Program Design</li>
	  <li>Modified website</li>
	  <li>PDF Conversion Engine</li>
	</ul>
      </p>
      
      <a name="ppro"/><h4>4. Project Process</h4>
      
      <p>
	Following feasibility and requirements analysis, we plan to produce an 
	initial prototype of the system to show to the client to confirm developer 
	thoughts on the project. After the prototype, we will move on to systems and 
	program design and coding phases. Unfortunately, due to the nature of the legal
	data, there is not comprehensive test plan. At the end, we will conduct documentation
	and debugging as well as acceptance testing. 
      </p>

      <a name="res"/><h4>5. Resources</h4>

      <p>
	Software:
	<ul>
	  <li>XSLT Engine</li>
	  <li>PDG Shopping cart</li>
	  <li>XML</li>
	  <li>Verisign Pay Flow</li>
	  <li>XSL/FO Processor (PDF Generation)</li>
	  <li>Apache server</li>
	  <li>CVS</li>
	  <li> Linux</li>
	</ul>
      </p>
      <p>
	Hardware:
	<ul>
	  <li>1 server (lula.law.cornell.edu) used for project development and as
	    a server for the concurrent version control system (CVS).</li>
	</ul>
      </p>
      <p>
	Facilities and Tools
	<ul>
	  <li>Regular meetings Mondays 5-7 in Upson Hall or the Law School</li>
	  <li>Yahoo groups: cs501 (http://groups.yahoo.com/group/cs501/) 
	    egroup for message board and limited file sharing capabilities</li>
	  <li>CVS Repository on lula.law.cornell.edu will be used for development</li>
	</ul>
      </p>

      <FOOTER>
	<PATH>resources/cs501</PATH>
      </FOOTER>
    </CONTENT>

    <RIGHTPANEL>
    </RIGHTPANEL>
  </BODY>
</HTMLPAGE>
</DOC>

